♪ I know you
♪ I walked with you
once upon a dream
♪ I know you
♪ The gleam in your eyes
is so familiar a gleam
♪ Yet I know it's true
♪ That visions are seldom
all they seem
♪ But if I know you
I know what you'll do
♪ You'll love me at once
♪ The way you did
once upon a dream ♪
NARRATOR:
In a faraway land long ago,
lived a king
and his fair queen.
Many years had they longed
for a child,
and finally
their wish was granted.
A daughter was born,
and they called her Aurora.
♪ Sweet Aurora ♪
NARRATOR:
Yes, they named
her after the dawn,
for she filled their
lives with sunshine.
Then a great holiday
was proclaimed
throughout the kingdom,
so that all
of high or low estate
might pay homage
to the infant princess.
And our story begins
on that most joyful day.
♪ On that joyful day
♪ On that joyful day ♪
(BELLS CHIMING)
♪ Joyfully now
to our princess we come
♪ Bringing gifts
and all good wishes too
we pledge our loyalty anew
♪ Hail to
the Princess Aurora
♪ All of her subjects
adore her
♪ Hail to the King
Hail to the Queen
♪ Hail to
the Princess Aurora
♪ Health to the Princess
Wealth to the Princess
♪ Long live
the Princess Aurora
♪ Hail, Aurora
♪ Health to the Princess
Wealth to the Princess
♪ Long live
the Princess Aurora
♪ Hail to the King
Hail to the Queen
♪ Hail to
the Princess Aurora ♪
NARRATOR: Thus, on this
great and joyous day
did all the kingdom celebrate
the long-awaited royal birth.
And good King Stefan
and his queen
made welcome
their lifelong friend.
(TRUMPETS BLOWING)
Their royal highnesses,
King Hubert
and Prince Phillip!
NARRATOR: Fondly had
these monarchs dreamed one
day their kingdoms to unite.
Thus, today would they
announce that Phillip,
Hubert's son and heir,
to Stefan's child
would be betrothed.
And so to her
his gift he brought.
And looked unknowing
on his future bride.
(TRUMPETS BLOWING)
HERALD:
Their most honored
and exalted excellencies,
the three good fairies!
Mistress Flora!
Mistress Fauna!
And Mistress Merryweather!
Oh.
The little darling.
FAIRIES: Your Majesties.
Each of us
the child may bless
with a single gift,
no more, no less.
Little princess,
my gift shall be
the gift of beauty.
♪ One gift
♪ Beauty rare
♪ Gold of sunshine
in her hair
♪ Lips that shame
the red, red rose
♪ She'll walk with springtime
wherever she goes ♪
Tiny princess,
my gift shall be
the gift of song.
♪ One gift
♪ The gift of song
♪ Melody her whole life long
♪ The nightingale's
her troubadour
♪ Bringing his sweet serenade
to her door ♪
Sweet princess,
my gift shall be...
(WIND HOWLING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
FAUNA:
Why, it's Maleficent.
What does she want here?
Shh.
Well, quite a glittering
assemblage, King Stefan.
Royalty, nobility,
the gentry and...
(CHUCKLES)
How quaint.
Even the rabble.
(GRUNTS IN ANGER)
I really felt
quite distressed at not
receiving an invitation.
You weren't wanted.
Not want...
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, dear, what an
awkward situation.
I had hoped
it was merely due
to some oversight.
Well, in that event,
I'd best be on my way.
And, you're
not offended,
Your Excellency?
Why, no, Your Majesty.
And to show
I bear no ill will,
I, too, shall bestow
a gift on the child.
Listen well, all of you.
The princess shall indeed
grow in grace and beauty,
beloved by
all who know her.
But,
before the sun sets
on her 16th birthday,
she shall prick her finger on
the spindle of a spinning
wheel and die!
Oh, no!
(CACKLING)
Seize that creature!
Stand back, you fools!
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(EVIL LAUGHTER)
Don't despair,
Your Majesties.
Merryweather still
has her gift to give.
Then she can undo
this fearful curse?
Oh, no, sire.
Maleficent's powers
are far too great.
But she can help.
But...
FAUNA:
Just do your best, dear.
FLORA: Yes, go on.
Sweet princess,
if through this
wicked witch's trick
a spindle should
your finger prick,
a ray of hope there
still may be in this,
the gift I give to thee.
Not in death,
but just in sleep.
The fateful prophecy
you'll keep.
And from this slumber
you shall wake,
when true love's kiss
the spell shall break.
♪ For true love
♪ Conquers all ♪
NARRATOR:
But King Stefan,
still fearful of
his daughter's life,
did then and there decree
that every spinning wheel
in the kingdom
should on that
very day be burned.
So it was done.
Oh, silly fiddle-faddle.
Now,
come have a nice
cup of tea, dear.
I'm sure it'll
work out somehow.
Well,
a bonfire won't
stop Maleficent.
Of course not.
But what will?
Well,
perhaps if we
reason with her.
Reason?
With Maleficent?
Well, she can't
be all bad.
Oh, yes, she can!
Oh, I'd like to turn her
into a fat, old hoptoad.
Now, dear,
that isn't a very
nice thing to say.
Besides, we can't.
You know our magic
doesn't work that way.
It can only do good, dear,
to bring joy and happiness.
Well, that would
make me happy.
But there must be some way.
There is!
There is?
What is it, Flora?
I'm going to...
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
Even walls have ears.
Follow me.
I'll turn her
into a flower.
Maleficent?
(GIGGLES)
Oh, no, dear.
The princess.
Oh, she'd make
a lovely flower.
Don't you see?
A flower can't
prick its finger.
It hasn't any.
That's right.
FLORA: She'll be
perfectly safe.
Until Maleficent
sends a frost.
(LAUGHS) Yes, uh...
Oh, dear.
She always ruins
your nicest flowers.
You're right.
And she'll be
expecting us to do
something like that.
(GROANS) Well, what
won't she expect?
She knows everything.
Oh, but she doesn't, dear.
Maleficent
doesn't know
anything about love,
or kindness or the joy
of helping others.
You know, sometimes
I don't think she's
really very happy.
That's it!
Of course.
It's the only thing
she can't understand
and won't expect.
(GIGGLING)
Now, now, we'll have
to plan it carefully.
Let's see.
The woodcutter's cottage,
yes, yes, the abandoned one.
Of course, the King
and Queen will object.
But when we explain
it's the only way...
(ECHOING)
Explain what?
About
the three peasant women
raising a foundling child
deep in the forest.
Oh, that's
very nice of them.
Who are they?
Turn around.
(GASPING)
Why, it's us!
Uh-huh.
You mean, "we" us?
Take care of the baby?
FLORA: Why not?
FAUNA:
Oh, I'd like that.
(STUTTERS) Well, yes,
but we'd have to feed it.
And wash it and dress it
and rock it to sleep.
Oh, I'd love it.
You really think we can?
If humans can do it,
so can we.
And we'd have our
magic to help us.
FAUNA: That's right.
No, no, no, no, no!
No magic.
I'll take those
wands right now.
Oh, better get rid
of those wings, too.
You mean live
like mortals?
For 16 years?
FLORA: Uh-huh.
Now, now,
we don't know how.
We've never
done anything
without magic.
That's why Maleficent
will never suspect.
But who'll wash?
And cook?
Oh, we'll all pitch in.
I'll take care
of the baby.
Let me have it, dear.
Come along now. We must
tell Their Majesties
at once.
Flora?
MERRYWEATHER: Flora?
NARRATOR:
So, the King and his queen
watched with heavy hearts
as their most
precious possession,
their only child,
disappeared into the night.
Many sad and lonely
years passed by
for King Stefan
and his people.
But as the time
for the princess's
16th birthday drew near,
the entire kingdom
began to rejoice.
For everyone knew that as
long as Maleficent's domain,
the Forbidden Mountains,
thundered with her wrath
and frustration,
her evil prophecy
had not yet been
fulfilled.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
It's incredible!
Sixteen years,
and not a trace of her!
She couldn't have
vanished into thin air!
Are you sure
you searched
everywhere?
(SNORTS) Yes, uh, yes,
everywhere. We all did.
Yes, yes.
(ALL BABBLING)
And what about the town?
The forest? The mountains?
Uh, we searched mountains,
forests...
And houses and, uh...
Let me see.
And all the cradles.
Cradle?
(LAUGHS) Yep, yep.
Every cradle.
Cradle!
Did you hear
that, my pet?
All these years they've
been looking for a baby.
(HYSTERICAL LAUGHTER)
(LAUGHING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Fools!
(SNORTS)
Idiots! Imbeciles!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
(SIGHS IN DISAPPOINTMENT)
Oh, they're hopeless.
A disgrace to
the forces of evil.
(SIGHS) My pet.
You are my last hope.
Circle far and wide.
Search for a maid of 16,
with hair of sunshine gold
and lips red as the rose.
Go, and do
not fail me.
NARRATOR: And so,
for 16 long years,
the whereabouts
of the princess
remained a mystery.
While deep in the forest,
in a woodcutter's cottage,
the good fairies carried out
their well-laid plan.
Living like mortals,
they had reared the
child as their own,
and called her Briar Rose.
(HUMMING)
NARRATOR: On this,
her 16th birthday, the good
fairies had planned a party.
And something extra
special for a surprise.
Well, how about
this one?
This is the one
I picked.
Oh, she'll look
beautiful in that.
Now, I thought
a few changes here.
Uh-huh.
FAUNA: Don't forget
a pretty bow.
Yes, and raise
the shoulder line.
We'll make it blue.
Oh, no, dear, pink.
But...
Of course,
we need a few pleats.
MERRYWEATHER:
Yes, but how are we gonna
get her out of the house?
FLORA:
I'll think of something.
(FAIRIES GIGGLING)
Well, and what are you
three dears up to?
Up to?
(STAMMERING)
Well, well, we...
We want you to
pick some berries.
That's it! Berries!
Berries?
Lots of berries.
But I picked
berries yesterday.
FLORA: Oh, we need more, dear.
FAUNA: Lots, lots more.
FLORA: (GIGGLES) Yes.
Now, don't hurry back, dear.
But don't go too far.
And don't speak
to strangers.
FAUNA: Goodbye, dear.
MERRYWEATHER: Goodbye.
FLORA: Goodbye.
Goodbye.
I wonder
if she suspects.
Of course not.
Come on.
(LAUGHING)
Will she be surprised.
A real birthday party.
With a real birthday cake.
Yes, and a dress
a princess can
be proud of.
I'll get the wands.
Yes, you can, uh...
The wands?
Oh, no!
FLORA: No magic!
But the 16 years
are almost over.
We're taking no chances.
But I've never baked
a fancy cake.
Oh, you won't
have to, dear.
I'm going to
bake the cake.
You?
Now, she's always
wanted to, dear.
And this is
her last chance.
Well...
I'm going to make it
15 layers with pink
and blue forget-me-nots.
And I'm making
the dress.
But you can't sew,
and she's never cooked.
(LAUGHING) It's simple.
All you do is
follow the book.
Up here, dear.
You can be the dummy.
Well, I still say
we ought to use magic.
(LAUGHS)
(HUMMING)
"Flour, three cups."
Cups, cups, cups,
cups, cups, cups.
Oh.
(HUMMING)
One, two, three.
What's that for?
Well, it's got to have
a hole in the bottom.
FAUNA: That's for
the feet to go through.
It's pink!
Oh, lovely shade,
isn't it?
But I wanted it blue.
(GRUNTS)
Now, dear,
we decided pink
was her color.
You decided!
(CHUCKLES)
(GRUNTING)
(MUTTERING ANGRILY)
(HUMMING)
"Two eggs, fold in gently."
Fold? Oh, well.
(HUMMING)
(SHELLS CRACKING)
(MUFFLED)
I can't breathe!
Let me out of here.
It looks awful.
That's because
it's on you, dear.
"Now, yeast, one tsp."
"Tsp?"
One teaspoon.
(GIGGLING) Oh,
one teaspoon,
of course.
(HUMMING)
Oh, gracious,
how that child
has grown.
Oh, it seems
only yesterday
we brought her here.
Just a tiny baby.
(SNIFFLES)
Why, Merryweather.
Whatever is
the matter, dear?
(CRYING) After today
she'll be a princess,
and we won't have
any Briar Rose.
Oh, Flora.
Now, now, now, now.
Well, we all knew
this day had to come.
But why did it have
to come so soon?
After all,
we've had her
for 16 years.
Sixteen wonderful years.
(SNIFFLES)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Oh, gracious!
We're acting like
a lot of ninnies.
Come on. She'll be back
before we get started.
(VOCALIZING)
(CHIRPING TO THE SAME TUNE)
(AURORA VOCALIZING)
(CHIRPING)
(VOCALIZING)
(BOTH CHIRPING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(VOCALIZING CONTINUES)
(HOOTING)
(VOCALIZING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(AURORA VOCALIZING)
You hear that, Samson?
Beautiful.
(SNORTS)
What is it?
Come on. Let's find out.
(SNORTS)
Aw, come on.
For an extra
bucket of oats?
And a few carrots?
Hup, boy!
(AURORA VOCALIZING)
PHILLIP: Whoa!
(SNORTS)
(WATER SPLASHING)
No carrots.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(HUMMING)
♪ I wonder
♪ I wonder why
each little bird
♪ Has a someone
♪ To sing to
♪ Sweet things to
♪ A gay little love melody
♪ I wonder
♪ If my heart keeps singing
♪ Will my song go winging
♪ To someone
♪ Who will find me
♪ And bring back a love song
♪ To me ♪
(SIGHS) Oh, dear.
Why do they still
treat me like a child?
Who?
Aunt Flora and Fauna
and Merryweather.
They never want me
to meet anyone.
(GIGGLES)
But you know something?
(WHISPERING)
I fooled them.
I have met someone.
(BIRDS TWITTERING)
Who?
Who? Who?
Oh... A prince.
Well, he's tall
and handsome and...
And so romantic.
(CHIRPING)
Oh, we walk together
and talk together.
And just before
we say goodbye,
he takes me in his arms,
and then...
(EXCITED CHIRPING)
I wake up.
(DEJECTED CHIRPING)
Yes, it's only
in my dreams.
(SNIFFLES)
But they say if you dream
a thing more than once,
it's sure to come true.
And I've seen him
so many times.
(AURORA HUMMING)
(HOOTING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
PHILLIP: You know, Samson,
there was something
strange about that voice.
Too beautiful to be real.
Maybe it was a mysterious
being, a wood sprite, or...
(SNORTS)
(NEIGHS)
Here, stop!
(HUMMING)
(OWL HOOTING)
(GASPS)
AURORA: Why,
it's my dream prince.
(GIGGLING)
Your Highness.
(HUMMING)
You know, I'm really
not supposed to speak
to strangers.
But we've met before.
♪ I know you
♪ I walked with you
once upon a dream
♪ I know you
♪ The gleam in your eyes
is so familiar a gleam
♪ Yet I know it's true
♪ That visions are
seldom all they seem
♪ But if I know you
♪ I know what you'll do
♪ You'll love me at once
♪ The way you did
once upon a dream
♪ La, la, la, la, la
♪ But if I know you
♪ I know what you'll do
♪ You'll love me at once
♪ The way you did
♪ The way you...
♪ Once upon a dream ♪
(HOOTING)
Oh. Oh!
I'm awfully sorry.
I didn't mean to
frighten you.
Oh, it...
Wasn't that.
It's just that
you're, uh, uh...
A stranger?
AURORA: Mmm-hmm.
PHILLIP: But don't you
remember? We've met before.
We... We have?
Well, of course.
You said so yourself.
Once upon a dream.
♪ I know you
♪ I walked with you
once upon a dream
♪ I know you
♪ The gleam in your eyes
is so familiar a gleam
♪ And I know it's true
♪ That visions are seldom
all they seem
♪ But if I know you
♪ I know what you'll do
♪ You'll love me at once
♪ The way you did once
♪ Upon a dream ♪
Who are you?
What's your name?
Hmm?
Oh! My name.
Why, it's, it's...
Oh, no, no.
I can't. I...
Goodbye.
But when will
I see you again?
Oh, never, never!
PHILLIP: Never?
Well, maybe someday.
When? Tomorrow?
Oh, no!
This evening!
Where?
At the cottage in the glen.
(HUMMING)
There. Whoop!
Well, what do you
think of it?
Why, it's...
It's a very unusual
cake, isn't it?
Yes.
Of course, it'll be much
stiffer after it's baked.
Of course, dear.
Um, what do you
think of the dress?
Well, it's...
It's not exactly the way
it is in the book, is it?
Oh, I improved it.
But perhaps if I added
a few more ruffles...
What do you think?
Um, I think so.
What do you think,
Merryweather?
I think
we've had enough
of this nonsense!
I think we ought to
think of Rose and what
she'll think of this mess.
I still think
what I thunk before.
I'm going to
get those wands.
You know,
I think she's right.
(FOOTSTEPS PATTERING)
Here they are, good as new!
(STUTTERING)
Careful, Merryweather.
Quick, lock the doors.
Fauna, you close
the windows.
Oh, block up
every cranny.
We can't take any chances.
And now, you take
care of the cake.
While I...
Clean the room, dear.
And I'll make the dress.
Now hurry!
Ooh!
Come on,
bucket, mop, broom.
Flora says
clean up the room.
(MERRYWEATHER GIGGLES)
And now to make
a lovely dress,
fit to grace
a fair princess.
♪ Eggs, flour, mi... ♪
Just do it like it
says here in the book.
I'll put on the candles.
Oh, no, not pink.
Make it blue.
(GASPS)
Merryweather!
Make it pink.
(WHISPERS)
Make it blue.
Oh, pink.
Blue.
(SQUAWKING)
(EXCLAIMS) Now look
what you've done!
(AURORA HUMMING)
Shh. Listen.
It's Rose.
She's back.
Enough of
this foolishness.
Make it pink.
Now, hide, quick!
(WHISPERS) Blue.
Aunt Flora!
Good gracious!
Who left the mop running?
(GASPS) Stop, mop.
Aunt Flora, Fauna,
Merryweather.
Where is everybody?
(GASPS)
Oh!
FAIRIES: Surprise!
Happy birthday!
Oh, you darlings.
This is the happiest day
of my life.
Everything's so wonderful.
Just wait till you meet him.
Him?
Rose.
You...
You've met some stranger?
Oh, he's not a stranger.
We've met before.
You have?
Where?
Once upon a dream.
♪ I know you
♪ I walked with you
once upon a dream ♪
She's in love.
Oh, no.
This is terrible.
Why?
After all, I am 16.
It isn't that, dear.
You're already betrothed.
Betrothed?
Since the day you were born.
To Prince Phillip, dear.
But that's impossible.
How could I marry a prince?
I'd have to be...
A princess.
And you are, dear.
Princess Aurora.
Tonight,
we're taking you back to
your father, King Stefan.
But... But I can't.
He's coming here tonight.
I promised to meet him.
I'm sorry, child,
but you must never see
that young man again.
Oh, no! No!
I can't believe it!
(CRYING) No!
And we thought
she'd be so happy.
(SOBBING)
(DEEP SIGH)
No sign of her yet, Hubert.
Course not.
It's a good half hour
till sunset.
(BELCHES)
Ah, excellent bird.
Mmm.
Oh, now, come, man!
Buck up! Battle's over!
Girl's as good as here.
I'm sorry, Hubert,
but after 16 years
of worrying,
never knowing...
The past!
All in the past.
Tonight,
we toast the future,
with something
I've been saving
for 16 years.
(CHUCKLES)
Here, to the future.
STEFAN:
Right, Hubert.
To the future.
(KINGS LAUGHING)
♪ Skumps, skumps
♪ Skumps
♪ A toast to this night
♪ The outlook is rosy
♪ And the future is bright
BOTH:
♪ Our children will marry
Our kingdoms unite
♪ Skumps, skumps
♪ Skumps ♪
HUBERT: (SIGHS)
Ah, excellent vintage.
(HUBERT CHUCKLING)
(HICCUPS)
And now,
to the new home, eh?
New home?
Children need a nest
of their own, what?
Place to raise their
little brood, eh?
(HUBERT CHUCKLES)
STEFAN:
Well, I suppose in time...
HUBERT: Of course!
To the home!
♪ Skumps
♪ A toast to the home
♪ One grander by far
than a palace in Rome
Now, let me
fill up your glass.
That last was all foam.
♪ Skumps, skumps
♪ Skumps ♪
(KINGS SLURPING)
(KINGS LAUGHING)
(HUBERT CLAPS)
The plans!
(HICCUPS)
Well, what do you think?
Nothing elaborate,
of course.
Forty bedrooms, dining hall.
Honeymoon cottage, really.
You... You mean,
you're building
it already?
Built, man! Finished!
Lovebirds can
move in tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
But, Hubert, they're
not even married yet.
(LAUGHS) Take care
of that tonight.
To the wedding!
Now, hold on, Hubert.
I haven't
even seen my
daughter yet,
and you're taking her
away from me.
HUBERT: Getting my
Phillip, aren't you?
STEFAN: Yes, but...
HUBERT: Want to see our
grandchildren, don't we?
Of course, but...
There's no time to lose.
Getting on in years.
(LAUGHING)
To the wedding!
STEFAN: Now,
be reasonable,
Hubert.
After all, Aurora knows
nothing about all this.
Well?
Well, it may come
as quite a shock.
(GAGS) Shock?
My Phillip, a shock?
What's wrong
with my Phillip?
Nothing, Hubert.
I only meant...
Why doesn't your
daughter like my son?
Now, now...
I'm not so sure
my son likes
your daughter!
Now, see here.
I'm not so sure
my grandchildren
want you for
a grandfather!
Why, you,
you unreasonable...
Huh?
...pompous, blustering,
old windbag!
Who? Uh...
Unreasonable, pompous,
en garde, sir!
I warn you, Hubert.
This means war.
Forward! For honor!
For country! For...
(BOTH LAUGHING)
What's this
all about anyway?
(CHUCKLES)
Nothing, Hubert.
Absolutely nothing.
Children bound to fall
in love with each other.
Precisely. And as
for grandchildren,
I'll have the royal
woodcarvers start work
on the cradle tomorrow.
Splendid!
King-size, of course.
Certainly.
To the woodcarvers' guild.
(LUTE STRINGS VIBRATING)
(SNORING)
(LUTE VIBRATING)
MAN: His royal highness
Prince Phillip!
Phillip?
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
Phillip!
Phillip, ho, Phillip!
(PANTING)
Hurry, boy, hurry.
Change into
something suitable.
Can't meet your future
bride looking like that.
But I have met her, Father.
You have? Where?
Once upon a dream.
(HUMMING)
Oh, Phillip, stop it.
Stop that! Phillip!
Put me down.
Now, what's all this
dream nonsense?
It wasn't a dream, Father.
I really did meet her.
Princess Aurora?
Good heavens,
we must tell Stefan.
Why, this is the most...
I didn't say it was Aurora.
You most certainly did.
You said...
I said, I met the girl
I was going to marry.
I don't know who she was.
A peasant girl, I suppose.
(STUTTERING) A peasant girl?
You're going to marry a...
Why, Phillip.
(NERVOUS LAUGH)
You're joking.
Isn't he?
No! You can't
do this to me!
Give up the throne,
the kingdom,
for some, some nobody?
By Harry,
I won't have it!
You're a prince,
and you're going
to marry a princess!
Now, Father,
you're living
in the past.
This is the 14th century.
Nowadays...
Nowadays,
I'm still the king
and I command you
to come to your senses!
And marry
the girl I love?
Exactly!
Goodbye, Father.
Marry the girl you...
No, no!
No, no, Phillip!
Stop! Come back!
Oh, Phillip!
(ECHOING) Phillip!
(GROANS) Oh, ho.
Oh, how will I
ever tell Stefan?
(WHISPERING)
Come along now.
All right.
In here, dear.
(SIGHS)
FLORA:
Bolt the door,
Merryweather.
Fauna,
pull the drapes.
And now, dear,
if you'll just
sit here.
This one last gift,
dear child, for thee.
The symbol
of thy royalty.
A crown to wear
in grace and beauty
as is thy right
and royal duty.
(SOBBING)
Now, dear...
Come.
Let her have
a few moments alone.
It's that boy she met.
Whatever are we
going to do?
Oh, I don't see why
she has to marry
any old prince.
Now, that's not for
us to decide, dear.
Maybe we should
tell King Stefan
about the boy.
Well, why don't we?
Listen! Maleficent!
Rose!
ALL: (GASPING) Rose!
FAUNA: Oh, why did
we leave her alone?
ALL: Rose!
(ALL GRUNTING)
Here.
ALL: Rose!
ALL: Rose. Where are you?
ALL: (ECHOING) Rose!
(ECHOING) Rose!
Rose!
ALL: Rose!
FAUNA: Rose!
FLORA: (ECHOING) Rose,
don't touch anything!
MALEFICENT:
Touch the spindle.
Touch it, I say!
(ALL GASPING)
You poor, simple fools,
thinking you could defeat me!
Me!
The mistress of all evil!
Well, here's your
precious princess!
(SINISTER LAUGHTER)
Rose.
Oh, Rose.
FLORA: (CRYING)
Oh, I'll never
forgive myself.
FAUNA: (CRYING)
We're all to blame.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Stefan, there's...
There's
something important
I have to tell you.
Not now, Hubert.
But it's about Phillip.
Phillip? Oh, yes,
of course, Phillip.
Why, where is the boy?
That's what I'm
trying to tell you.
Well, send for him
immediately!
But...
Shh!
(TRUMPETS BLOWING)
HERALD: The sun has set!
Make ready to welcome
your princess!
(CROWD CHEERING)
(ALL SOBBING)
Poor King Stefan
and the Queen.
They'll be heartbroken
when they find out.
They're not going to.
MERRYWEATHER:
They aren't? But...
We'll put them all to
sleep until Rose awakens.
Come.
♪ Sleeping beauty fair
♪ Gold of sunshine
♪ In your hair
♪ Lips that shame
♪ The red, red rose
♪ Dreaming of true love
♪ In slumber repose
♪ One day
♪ He will come
♪ Riding out of the dawn
♪ And you'll awaken
♪ To love's first kiss
♪ Till then, sleeping beauty
♪ Sleep on
♪ One day you'll awaken
♪ To love's first kiss
♪ Till then, sleeping beauty
♪ Sleep on ♪
(YAWNING)
Well, just been
talking to Phillip.
Seems he's fallen
in love with some
peasant girl.
Peasant girl?
Yes? Yes?
The peasant girl?
Who is she?
Where did he meet her?
Just some peasant girl
he met...
Where? Where?
(YAWNING)
Once upon a dream.
Once upon a...
Rose! Prince Phillip!
Oh! Oh!
Come on. We've got to
get back to the cottage.
(WHISTLING ONCE UPON A DREAM)
WOMAN: Come in.
(GOONS BABBLING)
(GRUNTING)
(CAWING)
Well!
This is
a pleasant surprise.
I set my trap
for a peasant
and, lo,
I catch a prince!
(CACKLING)
Away with him.
But gently, my pets. Gently.
(GOONS GRUNTING)
I have plans
for our royal guest.
(ALL GASP)
ALL: (GASPING) Maleficent!
She's got Prince Phillip.
At the Forbidden Mountain.
(GASPING)
But we can't,
we can't go there.
We can,
and we must!
(SNORTS)
(GOONS CHATTERING)
What a pity
Prince Phillip
can't be here
to enjoy
the celebration.
(CHUCKLING)
Come.
We must go
to the dungeon
and cheer him up.
Oh, come now,
Prince Phillip.
Why so melancholy?
A wondrous future
lies before you.
You, the destined hero
of a charming
fairy tale come true.
Behold,
King Stefan's castle.
And in yonder
topmost tower
dreaming of
her true love,
the Princess Aurora.
But see
the gracious
whim of fate.
(CHUCKLES) Why, 'tis
the selfsame peasant
maid
who won the heart of our
noble prince but yesterday.
She is indeed
most wondrous fair.
Gold of sunshine
in her hair.
Lips that shame
the red, red rose.
In ageless sleep
she finds repose.
The years roll by.
But a hundred years
to a steadfast heart
are but a day.
And now, the gates
of the dungeon part
and our prince is
free to go his way.
Off he rides
on his noble steed
a valiant figure,
straight and tall
to wake his love
with love's first kiss
and prove that
true love conquers all!
(CACKLING)
Why, you, you...
Come, my pet.
Let us leave our noble prince
with these happy thoughts.
A most gratifying day.
For the first time
in 16 years
I shall sleep well.
(WHISPERING) Shh!
No time to explain.
Wait, Prince Phillip.
The road to true love
may be barred by still
many more dangers
which you alone
will have to face.
So arm thyself with this
enchanted Shield of Virtue.
And this mighty
Sword of Truth.
For these weapons of
righteousness will
triumph over evil.
Now, come.
We must hurry.
(SQUAWKING)
(CAWING)
(GOONS SHOUTING)
(NEIGHING)
(SQUAWKING)
Phillip, watch out!
(CAWING)
Silence!
You, tell those
fools to... No!
(GASPS) No!
FAUNA:
Watch out, Phillip!
Hurry!
Hurry, Phillip!
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(NEIGHING)
A forest of thorns
shall be his tomb.
Borne through the skies
on a fog of doom!
Now go with a curse
and serve me well.
Around Stefan's castle,
cast my spell!
(NEIGHING)
(CACKLING)
No! It cannot be!
(NEIGHING)
Now shall you deal with me,
O Prince.
And all the powers of hell!
(CACKLING)
(NEIGHING)
(GRUNTING)
Up! Up this way!
(SINISTER LAUGHTER)
Now, Sword of Truth,
fly swift and sure.
That evil die
and good endure!
(SCREAMING)
(SNORTING)
(ALL YAWNING)
Oh, uh...
Forgive me, Hubert.
The wine. Now, uh...
(CLEARS THROAT)
You were saying?
Huh? I was?
Oh, oh, yes.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Well, huh.
After all, Stefan,
this is the 14th century.
Yes. You said that
a moment ago.
Well, to come
right to the point.
My son Phillip says
he's going to marry...
(TRUMPETS BLOWING)
It's Aurora!
She's here!
(STUTTERS) And Phillip!
What does this mean, boy?
I don't...
But...
(ONCE UPON A DREAM PLAYING)
I don't understand.
(SNIFFLING)
Why, Fauna.
What's the matter, dear?
Oh, I just love
happy endings.
Yes, I do, too.
(EXCLAIMS) Blue?
Pink!
♪ I know you
♪ I walked with you
♪ Once upon a dream
(WHISPERS) Blue!
♪ I know you
♪ The gleam in your eyes
is so familiar a gleam
♪ Yet I know it's true
♪ That visions are seldom
all they seem
♪ But if I know you
I know what you'll do
♪ You'll love me at once
the way you did once
♪ Upon
♪ A dream ♪